International Center Records UA088
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
International Center Records
1953 -- 2012
1953 -- 1990
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
International Center
UA088
0.42 Linear Feet 1 box
3 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Administrative files and history; Brochures, pamphlets and publication materials; Annual reports; Statistics on foreign students, faculty, and research scholars; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
Since the 1950s, the International Center has facilitated college-wide intercultural exchange. The Center staff works to raise intercultural awareness, to increase the knowledge of immigration laws affecting the Tufts international community, and to advocate a campus climate that respects cultural differences.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records generated by the Tufts University International Center including correspondence, brochures, annual reports, and statistics.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Student Affairs and Services; Employment and Human Resources; Legal and Regulatory; Student life
- Administrative files and history, 1953 -- 1982; UA088.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes correspondence and administrative materials from the International Center. Also included are materials relating to the history of the Center.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - I-Center History, 1953 -- 1982; UA088.001.001.00001 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
- Brochures, pamphlets, and publication materials, 1980 -- 1986; UA088.002; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series includes materials promoting the work of the International Center.
  - Brochures, 1980 -- 1986; UA088.002.001.00002 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
- Annual Reports, 1973 -- 1991; UA088.003; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series includes Annual Reports of the International Center, and reports from the Summer Institute on American Language, Culture and University Life.
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1973 -- 1974; UA088.003.001.00003 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1974 -- 1975; UA088.003.001.00004 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1975 -- 1976; UA088.003.001.00005 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
    Missing page 4.
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1976 -- 1977; UA088.003.001.00006 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Final report - Summer Institute on American Language, Culture and University Life [Binder], 1978; UA088.003.001.00007 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1978 -- 1979; UA088.003.001.00008 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Observations of Tufts University International Office [Binder], 1979; UA088.003.001.00009 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Final report - Summer Institute on American Language, Culture and University Life [Binder], 1979; UA088.003.001.00010 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report including Dean of Students report and Internation Center [Binder], 1979 -- 1980; UA088.003.001.00011 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1980 -- 1981; UA088.003.001.00012 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1981 -- 1982; UA088.003.001.00013 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Final report and catalog - Summer Institute on American Language, Culture and University Life [Binder], 1982; UA088.003.001.00014 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1982 -- 1983; UA088.003.001.00015 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1983 -- 1984; UA088.003.001.00016 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report [Binder], 1985; UA088.003.001.00017 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1990 -- 1991; UA088.003.001.00018 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
- Statistics on foreign students, faculty and research scholars, 1955 -- 1995; UA088.004; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series includes lists of foreign students, faculty and other personnel. It also include annual statistical summaries produced by the Internation Center.
  - Foreign students [Binder], 1955 -- 1956; UA088.004.001.00019 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Foreign students [Binder], 1956 -- 1957; UA088.004.001.00020 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Foreign students [Binder], 1959 -- 1960; UA088.004.001.00021 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - List of foreign students and staff personnel [Binder], 1960 -- 1961; UA088.004.001.00022 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - List of foreign students and staff personnel [Binder], 1961 -- 1962; UA088.004.001.00023 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Master list of foreign students [Binder], 1963; UA088.004.001.00024 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Master list of foreign students [Binder], 1964; UA088.004.001.00025 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Master list of foreign students [Binder], 1965; UA088.004.001.00026 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - International Personnel, Fall Semester [Binder], 1969; UA088.004.001.00027 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - International Personnel, Fall Semester [Binder], 1970; UA088.004.001.00028 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - International Personnel [Binder], 1971 -- 1972; UA088.004.001.00029 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - International Personnel [Binder], 1972 -- 1973; UA088.004.001.00030 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - International Personnel [Binder], 1973 -- 1974; UA088.004.001.00031 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Statistics on International Students, Faculty and Research Scholars [Binder, 1 of 3], 1973 -- 1978; UA088.004.001.00032 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Statistics on International Students, Faculty and Research Scholars [Binder, 2 of 3], 1978 -- 1985; UA088.004.001.00033 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
  - Statistics on International Students, Faculty and Research Scholars [Binder, 3 of 3], 1985 -- 1995; UA088.004.001.00034 (Box UA088 Shared 1)
- Additional accessions, 2000 -- 2012; UA088.005
  - History of International Students at Tufts research, 2010 -- 2011; UA088-001
  - Alumni Stories and Interviews, 2009 -- 2012; UA088-002
  - Int'l Orientation host advisor training, 2000-08; UA088-003